(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
そんな感じだったよね
It was something like that, wasn't it?
うん
Yeah.
あ、ままま、今日はね、ちょっとあのゲーマーズでね、行きたい所があるんですけども
Well, today, I have a place I want to go to with the Gamers.
え？え？ゲーマーズ？
Eh? Eh? Gamers?
そう、ゲーマーズで。え？
Yes, with the Gamers. Eh?
ひとり足りなくない？
Isn't one person missing?
足りないっすよね、見当たらない…
We're missing someone. She's not here...
どこ見当たらない、ですか？
She's nowhere to be found, is she?
あ、ままま、ちょっとね、もう一人は置いときまして
Well, putting that other person aside for now...
置いとくの！？
Putting her aside!?
早速バス用意してますので
I've already prepared a bus.
バス！？
A bus!?
乗って行きましょう、レッツゴー！
Let's get on. Let's go!
うぇ～～い！
Uweeey!
よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
え、ガチの貸切バスじゃん
Whoa, it's a real chartered bus!
ガチのバスでございます
It is indeed a real bus.
遠足じゃん！遠足だ～！
It's a field trip! A field trip!
ちょっとみんなで後ろに乗って行きましょう
Let's all sit in the back.
えーすげー！どこ行くんだ、こんなんで？
Wow, amazing! Where are we going in this?
ころね～！
Korone~!
え？あるやんけ！嘘でしょ！？
Eh? You're here! No way!
どうしたの？
What happened?
みんな～、おあよ～おあよ～！
Everyone, ohyo~ ohyo~!
すんごい小っちゃくなっちゃってるけど…
You've become so small...
こんな姿になっちゃったぁ…
To think you'd end up in this state...
このころねを今日は連れていきま～す
I'm taking this Korone with us today.
え～！？え～！？
Eh~!? Eh~!?
よろしくね
Nice to meet you.
ちょっと苦しそうまであるけどね
She looks a bit cramped, though.
ごめんね、ころね
Sorry, Korone.
ということで、バスの中でございますけども
Anyway, we are now on the bus.
今日はこんな朝早くから集まって、どこに行くと思いますか？みんな
Where do you think we're going so early this morning?
いや、本当にさ、わかんないからさ
I really have no idea.
どこでしょ？フブキちゃんの実家
Where? Fubuki-chan's parents' house?
行かないわ！！なんでやねん！
No!! Why would we go there?!
違います違います。えー、違うの？
Wrong, wrong. Eh, it's not?
今日はですね、まあね、日頃いっぱい遊んでもらって
Today, well, since you always play with me...
みんなもお仕事大変な中なので、ゆっくりしてもらおうということで
...and work so hard, I want you to relax.
今回は…草津に行きます！
So this time... we're going to Kusatsu!
うぇ～～い！草津ぅぅ！？
Uweeey! Kusatsuuuu!?
草津と言えば？
And what is Kusatsu famous for?
温泉！？
Onsen!?
すごくない！？台本無いのにめっちゃ被ってるよ
Isn't that amazing!? We were perfectly in sync without a script!
ハモりまくってるｗ ハモり具合半端なかった今
We totally harmonized! That harmony was incredible just now.
ま、今回なぜ草津に行きたいかと言いますと
Well, as for why I wanted to go to Kusatsu...
我々さ、この長い付き合いの中で温泉行ったりさ
...we've known each other a long time and gone to hot springs...
そう、グランピングとか行ったりしたけど
...and even gone glamping together.
その時に「今後行きたい温泉どこが良い？」みたいな話をしたことがありまして
At those times, we talked about where we'd want to go next.
したっけ？そんな事。したよッ！！
Did we? We did!!
したんだよ！！白上は覚えてんだよ！
We did!! I remember it clearly!
ま、それで、行ったことないから草津温泉行きたいな、みたいな話を白上から確かしたんだよね
Well, since I've never been, I said I wanted to go to Kusatsu Onsen.
で、「草津もいいね」みたいな話で。なるほど
And you all said Kusatsu sounded good. I see.
なので、ま、今回これを機に草津温泉に行こうじゃないかと、いうことで
So, I took this chance for us to go to Kusatsu Onsen.
あ、まあじゃあ、フブキが行きたいからって事？
Oh, so it's because you wanted to go?
そうです。そういうことかあ、そうだよね
Yes. I see, that's how it is.
バスに揺られながらのんびりと草津へ向かおうと思いま～す
We'll relax on the bus and head towards Kusatsu.
もちろんここにいる、ころねも一緒なのでね
And of course, Korone here is with us too.
こんな姿になっちゃってｗ こんな姿になっちゃったからにはねｗ
Even in that form... since you're in that state...
ころねの心の声を、あら、どうだい？ちょっと聞いてみるね、一緒に
Let's hear Korone's inner voice. How is it? Let's listen together.
うれしいいい～！
I'm so happy~!
そんなんだったっけ！？うれしい、ころねも草津、すき～
Was it like that!? Happy, Korone also loves Kusatsu~
わあ、なんかすごいちょっと誇張されてるｗ
Wow, she's exaggerating a bit!
ころ様も喜んでる。喜んでる？喜んでる、おかゆが言うならまあそうか
Korone-sama is happy too. Happy? She is. Well, if Okayu says so.
喜んでる喜んでる。はい、ということでね
She's happy, she's happy. Well then.
このままのんびりのんびり行こうと思いま～す。イェーイ！草津だ！温泉！行くぞ！
We'll just take it easy. Yay! Kusatsu! Hot springs! Let's go!
バスに揺られること４時間
4 hours on the bus...
草津到着！
Arrived at Kusatsu!
あ、この先に行くと湯畑があるらしいんですよ
The Yubatake is just ahead.
湯畑？湯畑ってなに？湯葉？
Yubatake? What's that? Yuba (tofu skin)?
湯葉じゃないｗ
Not Yuba! (lol)
まあ見ていただいたら分かります。お湯がいっぱいあるから湯畑なんじゃない？
You'll see when we get there. It's called Yubatake because there's so much hot water.
そういうこと！
I see!
そういうこと！はい、もうすごーい！わー！すごい！
That's it! Wow, look at that! Wow! Amazing!
湯気が！本当だ、なんかモクモクしてる
Look at the steam! It really is, it's all billowy.
ね、ちょっと近く行ってみてーなー。匂いもすごい温泉の
I want to get a bit closer. The smell of the hot springs is strong too.
ね、硫黄の匂いがします。湯畑って感じします
Yeah, it smells like sulfur. It really feels like Yubatake.
え、どうなってんの、これ。すごーい！
Wow, what's going on here? Amazing!
うわぁ、うわぁ、すごい！
Whoa, whoa, incredible!
すごい、茹で卵の匂いする！
Wow, it smells like boiled eggs!
茹で卵の匂い。作ってんのかな？ここで。え、茹で卵？そんな大量に…？
The smell of boiled eggs. Are they making them here? Eh, boiled eggs? In such huge amounts...?
温泉！すごい凄まじい！うわ、こっちはこっちですごいね、めっちゃ綺麗！
Hot springs! This is incredible! Whoa, this side is amazing too, so beautiful!
うわぁ～！温泉の滝だぁ～！！
Whoa~! It's an onsen waterfall!!
うわぁ、温泉の滝、あっちすごいよ！ね、すごいダバーってなってる
Whoa, an onsen waterfall, that's incredible! It's gushing down!
ウォータースライダーみたいになってる。すごい、温泉ウォータースライダーだ！すごい！
It looks like a water slide. Incredible, an onsen water slide! Wow!
モクモクもすごーい！すごいね、めっちゃモアモアする！
The steam is incredible! It really is, it's so thick!
わ、モワッとする！うわぁぁ～！！
Whoa, it's so steamy! Uwaaaaa~!!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
じゃあね、良い感じに湯畑も撮れましたので、次の目的地に行きましょう！
Well, we got some good shots of the Yubatake, so let's head to our next destination!
お、はい！レッツゴー！ゴーゴー！レッツゴー！ゴーゴー！
Oh, okay! Let's go! Go! Go! Let's go! Go! Go!
次の目的地へ移動中
Moving to the next destination...
西の河原公園には何があるんですか？
What's in Sainokawara Park?
さぁ何があるでしょうね…？
Well, I wonder what's there...?
おいおい！
Hey, hey!
足湯だ！
A footbath!
あ、ここか
Ah, it's here.
足湯があるんですねぇ
There's a footbath, isn't there?
すげぇ
Amazing.
なんか地面から煙出てない？
Is that smoke coming out of the ground?
出てる～！
It is!
もしや温泉…？
Could it be a hot spring...?
掘ったら出る？
Would it come out if we dug?
あ、これ温泉じゃない？
Ah, isn't this a hot spring?
本当だ、温泉だね
You're right, it's a hot spring.
ここも温泉なの～！？
This is a hot spring too!?
すごい、これ温泉だ
Wow, this is a hot spring.
緑だな～
It's so green.
きれいだね
It's beautiful.
温かいですか？
Is it warm?
どう？熱い？
How is it? Is it hot?
温か〜い！！
It's wa~rm!!
全然触れる、温かさ
It's a temperature you can definitely touch.
あったかいくらいなんだ
So it's just warm.
あ、なんか…看板立ってるよ？
Ah, there's... a sign standing there.
お
Oh.
「鬼の相撲場」ってありますよ
It says "Ogre's Sumo Arena."
え？
Eh?
相撲しようぜ！ってこと？
Does it mean "Let's do sumo!"?
パン、相撲しようぜ！
Bam, let's do sumo!
パン、みんなでこの後
Bam, all of us together after this.
「稲荷神社」って書いてある
It says "Inari Shrine."
そうなんです、本日はこちらですね、目的地は
That's right, this is the place for today, our destination...
え、ここなの？
Eh, it's here?
こちらの「稲荷神社」で〜す！
...is this "Inari Shrine"!
そうなの？
Is that so?
はい！
Yes!
すっすと
Up we go.
登って…よいしょ
Climbing... heave-ho.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
お稲荷さんもマスクしてる！
Even the Inari-sama is wearing a mask!
本当だ！
It's true!
本当だ
It's true.
招福の砂
Luck-bringing Sand
こちらのですね、砂を、おうちに持って帰っておうちでまくと…
This sand, if you take it home and scatter it around your house...
ご利益があると、言われております
...it's said to bring divine blessings.
へぇ〜
Heh~.
まずはあれでしょう、お参りからですね、はい
First off, we should start with a prayer, right.
礼
Bow.
お賽銭あげる瞬間をもうわからなくなっちゃったけど
I missed the exact moment to give the offering, but...
お賽銭(忘)
Offering (forgot)
先にあげるんだった
I should have given it first.
You should have given it first.
そこでこちらの砂ですね
And so, this sand.
お砂袋
Sand bags
おお〜
Ooh~.
「スプーン一杯です。欲張るとご利益は半減してしまいます」
"One spoonful. If you're greedy, the blessings will be halved."
欲張りさんはダメだって！
It says being greedy is no good!
分かった
Got it.
スプーン一杯分持って帰りましょう
Let's take home one spoonful.
スプーン一杯
One spoonful.
はい
Yes.
じゃあ僕から
Well then, I'll go first.
取りすぎるとあれだから、こんぐらいにしようかな
Taking too much would be bad, so maybe this much.
はい、商売繁盛、家内安全…
Yes, business prosperity, family safety...
「心願成就」っていうのかな
...is it called "wish fulfillment"?
※心願成就
*Wish Fulfillment
厄除開運とか、交通安全、病気…
Evil-warding and good luck, traffic safety, sickness...
はい、取りました
Yes, I've taken some.
オーケー
Okay.
一杯、すりきりで
One spoonful, level.
はいはい
Yes, yes.
はい、お砂もね。ころねにも、砂を…
Yes, the sand too. For Korone too, the sand...
あ、じゃあ200円を！ころねにも200円！
Ah, then 200 yen! 200 yen for Korone too!
あ、じゃあころねのも
Ah, then for Korone...
じゃあころさんの分、僕がお願いしとくから。ちょっと待ってね
Then I'll pray for Koro-san's share. Wait a bit.
まずはお金を先に入れて…
First, put the money in...
はい、お願いします
Yes, please.
じゃあころさんの分の砂もね、あんまり入れすぎると良くないみたいだから
Then the sand for Koro-san too, it seems too much isn't good, so...
ちょっとだけ、こんぐらい、こんぐらい
Just a little, this much, this much.
ちょびっとだけ、お
Just a tiny bit, oh.
こんぐらい
This much.
オッケー
Okay.
お砂です
It's the sand.
あっ
Ah.
ころねの！
For Korone!
ありがと〜！！
Thank you~!!
ころさんの
For Koro-san.
温泉に向け出発
Departure for the Hot Spring
徒歩です
By foot
温泉へ向けてね…
Heading towards the hot spring...
足早に行きましょう！
Let's go quickly!
うわぁ〜、お
Waa~, oh.
フブキちゃ〜ん！！
Fubuki-cha~n!!
やめっ、やめる〜！
Stop, stop it~!
寄りかかり攻撃
Leaning attack.
フブキちゃんに引っ張ってもらおう
Let's have Fubuki-chan pull us along.
やめてくれぇ〜！！
Stop it~!!
坂です
It's a hill.
うわぁ〜！
Waa~!
うわぁ〜、激坂だぁ〜！！
Waa~, it's a super steep hill~!!
やばい、登ってくぞ
This is bad, we're climbing.
温泉の為に頑張ろう…！
Let's do our best for the sake of the hot spring...!
大股で歩くぞ…
Taking big strides...
温泉の為だ！！
It's for the hot spring!!
大股で、よいしょ、よいしょ
Big strides, heave-ho, heave-ho.
よいしょ、よいしょ。汗かいてんな〜！
Heave-ho, heave-ho. I'm sweating~!
入る気満々だぁ！
I'm totally ready to get in!
激坂だぁ…
It's a super steep hill...
坂続く
The hill continues.
たんぽぽぉ
Dandelion.
たんぽぽ、やばい
Dandelion, oh no.
やべしっ
Oh no
現実逃避し始めている
She's starting to escape from reality.
頑張ろうみんな、頑張ろう
Let's do our best everyone, let's do our best.
あ、でも景色はすごい！
Ah, but the view is amazing!
あ、確かに
Ah, you're right.
だいぶ登ってます
We've climbed quite a bit.
景色はいいわな、頑張ろう
The view is nice, let's keep going.
しばくらだぁ〜…
It's Shibakura...
おお〜、着いた…！
Ooh~, we made it...!
登頂成功
Successfully reached the top
ハア、頑張って登ってきましたね
Haa, we did our best climbing up here.
激坂を
That steep hill.
激坂を登りましたけども、大丈夫ですか？お二人とも
We climbed that steep hill, but are you two okay?
ハアッ、息も絶え絶えですよね…
Haah, we're totally out of breath, aren't we...
もう、ヘベ、とりあえず、あ、座って冷たい飲み物、飲みたい…
I'm just... wheeze... anyway, ah, I want to sit down and drink something cold...
温泉に入りに行きましょう！
Let's go into the hot spring!
こちらでございます
Here it is.
おお、なんかきれいな感じだ
Oh, it looks pretty nice.
そう、めちゃめちゃきれいな感じでございます。こちらをじゃあくぐって
Yes, it feels incredibly nice and clean. Let's pass through here...
ラビスタ草津ヒルズ
La Vista Kusatsu Hills
行きましょう！
...and go!
楽しみ
I'm looking forward to it.
ワクワク
So excited.
行ってみますか？
Shall we go in?
はい
Yes
よいしょ
Yo-ho
では、扉を抜けました。
Now, we've passed through the doors.
はい
Yes
おおー
Ohhh
すごい
Amazing
かわいい
Cute
よいしょ
Yo-ho
こんにちは〜！
Hello!
えーと、予約してた白上です。はい
Uh, I'm Shirakami, I have a reservation. Yes
本日デイユースプランでお待ちしておりました
We've been expecting you for the day-use plan today.
はい
Yes
お風呂のご案内いたしますので、どうぞ
I'll guide you to the baths, please follow me.
はい、行きましょう。では、はい
Yes, let's go. Well then, yes
失礼します
Excuse us
失礼しますと
Coming in
うわー、すごい、きれい
Wow, it's amazing, beautiful
じゃあ、ここで靴を脱ぐ感じですかね？
So, we take off our shoes here?
はい
Yes
暖かっ！！
It's warm!!
暖かいね！
It's warm, isn't it!
ねえ暖かい、中もう暖かいよ！
Yeah, it's warm. It's already warm inside!
よいしょ
Yo-ho
じゃあ、ここで激坂を登った疲れをちょっと癒しますか！
So, shall we heal the fatigue from climbing that steep slope here?
いぇーい！
Yay!
はい、行きます、温泉レッツゴー！
Alright, here we go, onsen let's go!
おおー、うぉー、すげー！うお、いいな。おおー
Ohhh, wow, amazing! Oh, this is nice. Ohhh
景色すごい綺麗
The scenery is so beautiful.
内風呂もあるんですけど、本日はこちら、露天風呂！
There are indoor baths too, but today, it's this, the outdoor bath!
おおー！いぇーい、すげー！露天風呂だ！
Ohhh! Yay, amazing! It's an outdoor bath!
わぁ〜すこ！
Wow, I love it!
おおーすごい、溢れてるよもう！
Oh, wow, it's already overflowing!
わー、めちゃめちゃ溢れている。わー！！
Wow, it's overflowing so much. Wow!!
寒っ！！！
It's cold!!!
うわー、めちゃめちゃ溢れてる。わーすごい、ジャバジャバだ
Whoa, it's overflowing so much. Wow, it's splashing everywhere.
あ、ほら、ムササビ遊びに来たら外返してあげて
Oh, look, if a flying squirrel comes to play, let's send it back outside.
あ、なるほど。なるほどね。わかりました
Ah, I see. I see. Got it.
入っちゃっていいですか？
Can we go in?
どうぞどうぞ、入ってください！どうぞ
Go ahead, please go in! Go ahead.
寒っ！
It's cold!
熱っ！
It's hot!
結構熱い
It's quite hot.
本当？
Really?
結構熱い。熱い
It's quite hot. It's hot.
あっちぃ〜！
It's hot!
熱っ！！！
It's hot!!!
あっちゃっちゃ、熱い、入らないと、はっはっはっ
Ah, hot hot hot, it's hot, I have to get in, ha ha ha
ぐあああああー！
Guaaaaaah!
尻尾ビリビリくるぅーー！
My tail is tingling!
すごいよこれ、尻尾が
This is amazing, my tail is...
尻尾がビリビリする
My tail is tingling.
これはビリビリする
This really tingles.
はー、すごい
Phew, wow.
すごい！
Amazing!
ジワジワするよね？
It's stinging/tingling, right?
ね、そうそうそう！
Yeah, exactly!
すごいジワジワする
It's really stinging.
これ効能なの？
Is this its effect?
なんだろうね
I wonder.
あ、高温だからなのかな？
Ah, maybe because it's high temperature?
すごいなんかバチバチするよね
It feels really snappy/tingly.
そうそうそう！
Exactly!
すごいお肌に染みるというか
It really soaks into the skin, or rather...
染みるよね
It stings, right?
これが気持ちいい...！
This feels good...!
濃い温泉って感じがするぅ〜
It feels like a rich hot spring.
へあーあー
Heaaaah
気持ちよっ
Feels so good.
あ！なんかぴゅってしてる！
Ah! Something is squirted!
わー！
Wow!
手で水鉄砲を作って水を飛ばすミオ
Mio makes a water gun with her hands and squirts water.
すげー、うめぇ
Amazing, so good
出ないんだけど
Mine won't come out
本当だ
You're right
すごいな
Amazing
うま！
So good!
水飛ばし、片手で出来るのすこ！！
Squirting water, I love that you can do it with one hand!!
すご、プロじゃーん！
Wow, you're a pro!
どうやってやってるの？
How do you do it?
ぴゅーん
Pyun
すげー
Amazing
えぇー、どんな特技
What, what a skill
ほら見て、三重奏
Look at this, a trio.
すげー、すごっ
Amazing, wow
なんでそんな飛ばせんの？すごっ
How can you squirt it like that? Wow
ぴゅーん
Pyun
両手だともっと勢いすごいけどね、あれ
It's even more powerful with both hands, but, oh
うわっ
Whoa
びちゃびちゃ
Soaked
すげー、もうびちゃびちゃだ。すごい
Amazing, you're already soaked. Amazing
ほいっ
There
はーい、お上手
Yes, you're good
両手なの？片手
Both hands? One hand
これはね、あの、あれですよ、センスありですよ！
This is, well, you have talent!
マジで？
Seriously?
僕のも見てー、うん。ほら
Look at mine too, yeah. Look
上がれ、上がれ、頑張れ頑張れ頑張れ
Go up, go up, come on, come on, come on
どう？センスあり？
How is it? Do I have talent?
「並」って感じです
It's "average".
なみ...？
Average...?
なみです
Average
うぇええ〜、並なの？並です
Waaaah, average? Average
一句出来たのでよろしいでしょうか？
I've come up with a haiku, may I?
おお、出た、ミオ川柳
Oh, it's out, Mio Senryu
じゃあいきましょう
Let's go then
かっぽん
Kappon
草津の湯
Kusatsu waters
ビリビリ来るのが
The tingling sensation
癖になる
Becomes a habit
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
癖になってきちゃったか
You've become addicted to it, huh
癖になっちゃった
I've become addicted
「草津」と「癖」がなんかちょっとね
"Kusatsu" and "kuse" (habit) are a bit...
そういうこと！？
Is that it!?
さすがだなあ〜
As expected~
そ、そうです。はい
Y-yes. Yes.
さすがだなぁ、俳句の企画してるだけあるなぁ、さすがっすね、はい
As expected, it shows you're doing the haiku project, you're the best, yes
かっぽん。おっ
Kappon. Oh
日々の疲れ
Daily fatigue
なんだか今日で
Somehow today
なくなりそう
Seems it'll disappear
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
かっぽん
Kappon
確かに無くなりそう
It definitely feels like it'll disappear
いいじゃん、かっぽん
That's good, kappon
かっぽん
Kappon
ゲーマーズ
Gamers
ゲームもいいけど
Games are good, but
湯も良いね
The bath is also nice
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
かっぽん
Kappon
足つりそうになった...！！
I almost got a cramp in my leg...!!
ミオーー！
Mio!!
なんでぇ？？
Why??
なんでぇ？
Why?
そろそろ上がりますか？
Shall we get out soon?
次がありますのでね
We have the next thing to do
はい、行きましょうかでは
Yes, shall we go then
名残惜しいけど...
I hate to leave, but...
良いお湯でした！
It was a good bath!
あっちあちだったね
It was piping hot
あっちあちだね
Piping hot, indeed
よいしょ
Yo-ho
ゆったり休憩タイム
Relaxing break time
っていうことで
So
温泉も上がりまして
we've finished the bath
ゆっくりしておりますけれども。どうでしたか？温泉
and are relaxing. How was it? The bath.
いやアッツアツだったねー
Wow, it was piping hot
アッツアツだったね
Piping hot, indeed
気持ちよかったぁ〜
It felt so good~
満足ですねぇ
Very satisfying
もう帰るだけかな？
Is it just going home now?
もう帰るね、もう帰るだけかな
Going home, just going home now
えー！？まだころねとも合流してないんですよ！？
What!? We haven't even met up with Korone yet!?
ねー
Right
まだころねとも合流してないんですよ!?
We haven't even met up with Korone yet!?
そういえばそうだった
Oh, that's right.
忘れてた
I forgot.
ころぬい... なんか布タイプのころねがいたから
Since there was "Koronui"... that cloth-type Korone.
今泳いで走って来てくれてるんだから!
She's swimming and running to get here right now!
マジかよ
No way!
このあとは宿泊所に行くんですけど
After this, we're going to our accommodation.
湯上がりにアイスが頂けるということで、さっきみんなでアイスをちょっと食べたんですけど
Since we can get ice cream after the bath, we all had some just now.
頂いちゃいましたね。ちょっと我慢できずにペロリと頂いちゃいました
We did. We couldn't help it and gobbled it right up.
チョコレートの飲み物もあったし
They had chocolate drinks too.
美味しかったよ〜!
It was delicious!
紅茶も頂いちゃいましたね
We had some black tea too.
紅茶も美味しい。めちゃめちゃ美味しい。至れり尽くせりなんですが...
The tea was delicious. So good. Such great hospitality...
このあとは宿泊するところに移動したいと思います
After this, we'll head to where we're staying.
果たして... テントなのか...?
And so... is it a tent?
えええ!?
Ehh!?
野宿かテントかってこと?
Meaning sleeping outside or a tent?
え、嘘でしょ?
Wait, you're kidding?
野宿とテントの二択やばくない?
Choosing between sleeping outside or a tent is crazy, isn't it?
なんの一体どこに泊まらされるのか
I wonder where on earth we're being made to stay.
でもす〜ごく良いところです!
But it's a really nice place!
マジ?
Really?
えぇ〜?
Whaa?
なのでこのままね、またあの坂を...
So now, let's go down that slope again...
えっ嘘でしょ!?
Wait, you're kidding!?
汗だくだくになっちゃうよ〜!
I'll be dripping with sweat!
...と思ったんですけどバスが来るそうです!
...is what I thought, but a bus is coming!
よっしゃあ! お迎え来てくれるの!?
Yes! They're coming to pick us up!?
優しい! 迎えに来てくれますのでね
So kind! They're coming for us.
今回はね、のんびりしたのでバスで行きましょう
We relaxed this time, so let's take the bus.
おおー! 至れり尽くせりだ!
Whoa! Such great service!
やったー!
Yay!
本日のお宿へ移動
Moving to today's accommodation
はい、ということで、つきました! 本日泊まるところはここでございます
Okay, so we've arrived! This is where we're staying today.
ここですか?
Is it here?
はい、こちらですね、「きむらや別邸」と言いましてプライベートコテージと...
Yes, this is "Kimuraya Bettei", a private cottage...
え!? プライベートコテージ!?
Eh!? A private cottage!?
そのような物があるんですね
So such a place exists.
今日はこちらに一泊します
We're staying here tonight.
すげー
Awesome.
入ってみましょう! レッツゴー!
Let's go in! Let's go!
おっ、おお〜すごい! 玄関広い! おおー
Oh! Wow, the entrance is spacious. Ohh.
えぇ〜なんか照明すごくなーい?
Wait, isn't the lighting amazing?
リビングも! すごいですよ! リビングだぁ〜!!
The living room too! It's great! It's the living room!!
すご〜い!
Wow!
広い! すっごーい!
It's big! Amazing!
はい、広いです! きれーい! めっちゃ広いじゃん
Yes, it's big! Beautiful! It's really spacious.
照明もおしゃれ!
The lighting is stylish too!
ねー、おしゃれな空間となっております。これすごーい
Yeah, it's such a stylish space. This is great.
こちら、なんとお風呂! 見てください、お風呂!
And here... a bath! Look at this bath!
うわぁ〜! すごい!
Whoa! Amazing!
なんとこちら源泉でございます!
And it's from the source!
本当だ! 源泉でございます
It really is! It's from the source.
源泉かけ流しでございます
It's free-flowing from the source.
すんげんだけどこれ〜
This is incredible.
ほかのところもどんどん見に行っていいかな?
Can we go check out the other parts too?
今日はこちらで一泊しようと思います。楽しみ!
We'll be staying the night here today. I'm looking forward to it!
みなさん、これキッチンがあるということは...?
Everyone, having a kitchen means...?
え??
Eh??
今日の晩御飯は...
For tonight's dinner...
みんなでご飯を作りま〜す!
We're all going to cook together!
えぇ〜!? 主にミオちゃんしか料理できないんじゃないの〜!?
Ehh?! But only Mio-chan can really cook, right?
いやいやいやいや、そんなことないだろ。内容にもよるでしょ
No, no, no, no! That's not true. It depends on what we're making.
今日はみんなでカレーを作っちゃおうかなと
I thought we'd all make curry today.
すごーい! カレーを!? ミオちゃんがんばって!!
Wow! Curry!? Mio-chan, good luck!!
おいおい! お前も頑張るんだよッ!
Hey! You have to do your best too!
普通のカレーじゃアレなのでね、ちょっとゲマズらしいカレーを...
Since regular curry is a bit boring, let's make a GAMZ-style curry...
ゲマズらしいカレー??
GAMZ-style curry??
アレンジは危険だぞ!!
Arranging it is dangerous!!
誰にも内緒でみんなひとりずつ入れたいものを買って入れてみよう! ということで
Everyone will buy one thing they want to add without telling anyone, and we'll put them in!
闇カレーってこと?
You mean Yami Curry?
そう、闇カレーです
Yes, Yami Curry.
フブキちゃんのことだから辛〜いの入れんじゃないの?w
Knowing Fubuki-chan, she's going to put something really spicy in.
食べられない物はまずいのでね、ちゃんとね
Adding inedible things would be bad, so we'll be careful.
美味しくなりそうな物をね、はい、やろうと思いますので
We'll use things that seem like they'll be tasty. Yes, let's do it!
しばし休憩
A brief break
ふぅ〜、ここでちょっとゆっくりしてましたけども
Phew, we relaxed for a bit here.
そうだねぇ...
Yeah...
どうした!? 軽く寝てたか??
What's wrong? Did you sleep for a bit??
軽くというか... 結構がっつり寝ちゃった
Not just a bit, I fell sound asleep.
まぁこのあともご飯も作るんだけど... おっ、なんか鳴ってる〜!
Well, we have to make dinner soon... Oh! Something's ringing!
電話? もしもし〜??
A phone? Hello??
もしもし〜??
Hello??
おおー! ころさん! ころね!! ころさん! ころね!!
Oh! Korone! Korone! Korone! Korone!
今楽しんでる〜??
Are you enjoying yourselves right now??
「楽しんでる?」じゃないよー! 今どこにいんの!?
It's not "are you enjoying"! Where are you now!?
今さっき仕事終わって
I just finished work.
それで今... 迷いながらもうすぐ着きそう!
And now, I'm wandering a bit but I'm almost there!
やっぱ走って来たのかもしれない!
Maybe she really did run here!
歩いてきた、歩いてきた
I walked. I walked.
ゆっくり来たんだw
You came slowly, then.
ごめん、あのさぁ、爪が伸びたのね
Sorry, listen... my nails grew.
え、どういうこと? なんの話?? 爪が伸びた...?
Eh, what do you mean? What are you talking about? Your nails grew...?
爪が伸びたから、爪切りあったら置いといて欲しい
Since they grew, if you have nail clippers, I want you to put them out.
爪切りあったかなぁ、どうだったかなぁ
I wonder if there are any nail clippers?
爪切りがあったらよろ〜
Please check for nail clippers!
じゃあちょっと聞いとくね
Okay, I'll ask about it.
じゃあ待ってるよ〜!
Then, I'm waiting!
あー待っててねー!
Okay, wait for us!
はーい!
Bye!
ころね到着
Korone arrives
だいてさ... おっ、なんか来たよ
Well then... oh! Someone's here.
いいよ〜入ってきて
It's okay, come in.
お!
Oh!
ころね？もしかして
Is it Korone, perhaps?
到着したのか？
Did you arrive?
爪大丈夫だった？？
Were your nails okay??
いや、今の感じじゃ見えなかったけどね、爪は
Well, I couldn't really see them just now, your nails.
本当に？
Really?
キタ〜〜！！
I'm here~~!!
やったー！ごめんね！
Yay! Sorry!
やっと来たじゃ〜ん！
You finally came!
爪見して？ほら
Show me your nails? See...
言うほど伸びてないｗ
They're not as long as you said lol
何してたの？
What were you doing?
寝てたよ
I was sleeping.
寝てたの？
You were sleeping?
荷物さ、みんな無くね？
Wait, doesn't everyone not have their luggage?
上に置いちゃってんだ
They're all placed upstairs.
上行こ〜
Let's go upstairs~
この後何にするの？
What are we doing after this?
みんなでご飯を買いに行くよ
We're all going to buy food together.
ご飯買いに行くの？
Going to buy food?
今日ご飯作るんだよ
Today we're making a meal.
「何にもなってないやつ」を買うの？
Are we buying "things that haven't become anything yet"?
「何にもなってないやつ」ｗ
"Things that haven't become anything yet" lol
材料を買ってここで作るんだよ！
We buy ingredients and make it here!
聞いてねぇ！！ころねっ！？
I didn't hear about that!! Korone!?
夕飯の買い物へ出発
Heading out to shop for dinner
買ってきました
We bought the items.
まずは基本の材料
First, the basic ingredients.
カレールー
Curry roux.
にんじん
Carrots.
たまねぎ
Onions.
じゃがいも
Potatoes.
ここに追加する食材を発表！
Announcing the additional ingredients!
鶏肉
Chicken.
パプリカ
Paprika.
ナス
Eggplant.
たまご
Eggs.
ほたて
Scallops.
鶏肉
Chicken.
シーフードミックス
Seafood mix.
お肉買ってくるとは思わなくて…
I didn't think anyone would buy meat...
天然えび（デカいヤツ）
Wild shrimp (the huge ones)
シーフード鶏カレーってこと？
So it's a seafood chicken curry?
お料理開始
Start cooking
お肉を切りま〜す
I'm going to cut the meat~
やばい難易度高いよころさ〜ん！
This is bad, the difficulty is high, Koro-san~!
皮なんか切ったことないよ〜…
I've never cut a skin before~...
おかゆが作ったのがねみんな食べたいから
Because everyone wants to eat what Okayu makes.
ミオはナン作りを担当
Mio is in charge of making naan.
今ちょっとカオス状態だよ
It's a bit of a chaotic state right now.
まじか
Seriously?
じゃがいもの皮ってどうやって剥くんだろ
How do you peel potato skin?
芽は取ってね？芽は
Take out the eyes, okay? The eyes.
芽？芽ってどれ？これ？
Eyes? Which ones are the eyes? This?
豪快だ…
It's dynamic...
猫又おかゆの豪快Cooking!!
Nekomata Okayu's Dynamic Cooking!!
豪快じゃない…！！
It's not dynamic...!!
そんな風に思ってた？
Were you thinking that?
おまえを食ってやろうか！
Shall I eat you!
おまえを食ってやるー！！
I'll eat you~~!!
３匹になった！
There are three of them!
ダメだよご飯で遊んじゃ！！
You can't play with food!!
もっちもちだねぇ
It's so springy.
じゃあうちは１５分寝かせてる間シャボン玉をしてきます
Well, while I let it sit for 15 minutes, I'm going to blow some bubbles.
シャボン玉しちゃお〜
Let's blow bubbles~
白上フブキが吹いてるシャボン玉です。綺麗でしょう？
These are the bubbles Shirakami Fubuki is blowing. Beautiful, isn't it?
シャボン玉が目にッ！ああああ！
A bubble in my eye! Aaaah!
良いじゃなっすかぁ？
Looking good, isn't it?
ナスはヘタだけ取ったらいいのかな？そだよ〜
Should I just take the stems off the eggplants? That's right~.
ナン担当のミオ。カレーをみんなに任せて休憩中
Mio, in charge of naan. Resting while leaving the curry to everyone.
疲れたので少し休憩しております
I'm tired, so I'm resting for a while.
ミオしゃｗｗ
Mio-sha lol
でもやっぱ気になる
But I'm still curious.
経験者として口出そうとしちゃったけど…
I almost spoke up as an experienced person...
そしたらぁ！
In that case...!
たまねぎをまず炒めて
First, fry the onions.
First, sauté the onions.
鶏肉は別のフライパンで炒めて焦げ目付けといた方がいいよ
It's better to sauté the chicken in a separate pan to brown it.
なるほど〜？
I see...
確かに
True.
たまねぎある程度炒まったら
Once the onions are sautéed to a certain extent...
にんじんとパプリカも一緒に炒めちゃって
Sauté the carrots and bell peppers together with them.
なるほど〜
Got it.
頑張って炒めて。頑張って。
Do your best sautéing. Good luck.
僕の切ったナスです
These are the eggplants I cut.
ナス〜！
Eggplant!
ナス！
ナス見てころさん！ここ切れ目入れたんだよ！
Look at the eggplant, Koro-san! I made scores here!
あ、切れ目入れたのね！えらいねぇ〜！！
Oh, you scored them! Good girl!!
切れ目職人おかゆんが！
Okayun the scoring master!
おかゆ料理上手いもんね！！
Okayu is a great cook, after all!!
...ありがと
...Thanks.
なによぉｗ
What's that? lol
私もシーフード炒めたいと思います
I'd also like to sauté some seafood.
お願いします
Please do.
何故かカレー班に加わっている
Somehow she joined the curry team.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
うわすごい、エビ大占拠
Wow, look. The shrimp are taking over.
エビ軍すごいよ
The shrimp army is impressive.
エビ軍やばい
The shrimp army is crazy.
でかすじない？このエビ
Aren't these shrimp too huge?
でっかいエビ
Huge shrimp.
これの汁だけこの中に移動して
Just transfer the juices into here.
あーいいいね
Ah, that's good.
あとは焼きたいなちょっとやっぱり。オッケー
I'd still like to grill them a bit after all. Okay.
わ〜寝ちゃうこれ
Wow, I could fall asleep like this.
これ寝れるなあ。これ寝れる。
This is so sleepy. I can sleep here.
フブキちゃんを枕にしたら
If I use Fubuki-chan as a pillow...
ウヴァアアア！！
UWAAAAA!!
ちょうどいい
...it's just right.
あー助けてええ！
Ah, help meee!
ミオしゃパン屋さんみたい！
Mio-sha looks like a baker!
お前だろパン屋さんは
You're the baker here.
だはは！！
Dahaha!!
本当だよ
Seriously.
ちょっと一枚目を焼いて様子を見ております
I'm cooking the first one to see how it goes.
良い感じじゃ〜ん！！
Looking good!!
ナンナーン！！
Na-Naaan!!
ナンナーン
Na-Naaan.
ナンになったミオしゃです
I'm Mio-sha, who turned into Naan.
ミオしゃ〜？
Mio-sha~?
ナーン！！
NAAAN!!
ナンしゃって言ったらナンって言って
When I say 'Naan-sha', you say 'Naan'.
ミオしゃって呼んだら
And when I call 'Mio-sha'...
うちうち！うちうちだよって言うのよ
...you say 'Uchi-uchi! Uchi-uchi!'.
行くよ？
Ready?
ミオしゃ？
Mio-sha?
うちうち！
Uchi-uchi!
ミオしゃ？
Mio-sha?
うちうち！
Uchi-uchi!
ナンしゃ？
Naan-sha?
ナン！
Naan!
ナンしゃ？
Naan-sha?
ナーン！！
NAAAN!!
これ終わんの...？
Is this ever going to end...?
それ終わんの？ｗ
Does it ever end? lol
もう一個ないと！
You need one more variant!
ちょっと簡単すぎるよｗ
It's a bit too simple, lol.
特製ナン（カレー用）
Special Naan (for Curry)
形もすごいな
The shape is amazing too.
漢字がね、この広べったい感じがね。いいな
The feel of it, this flat feeling. It's nice.
着火！パーン！！
Ignition! Bam!!
ウオォーイ！！
Whoaaa!!
着火確認
Ignition confirmed.
アチャアアア！！
ACHAAAA!!
ゆっくり、ゆっくり
Slowly, slowly.
ゆっくりね
Be careful.
跳ねないように上からじゃなくてギリギリくらいまで持ってって〜
To avoid splashing, don't drop it from high up, bring it down close.
一個ずつね
One by one.
先生、ルー溶けました！
Sensei, the roux has melted!
溶けました？？
It's melted??
ほんとですか！？
Really!?
まだまだ塊ありそうだけどな...
It seems like there would still be chunks, though...
溶けたよ先生ルー...
It's melted, Sensei...
本当だ！！
It's true!!
早いね
That was fast.
消えんの早いね
It disappeared quickly.
美味しそう
Looks delicious.
早く浴びたいね
I want to bathe in it soon.
カレーを...？
The curry...?
頭から...？ｗ
From your head...? lol
頭はヤダね！
Not the head!
食道かな
The esophagus, then.
ああなるほどね？
Ah, I see?
口から...大げさな食事の表現だったのね？
From the mouth... It was just an exaggerated expression for eating?
流し込むってことね？
Meaning gulping it down?
そろそろ火消してもいいんじゃない？
I think we can turn off the heat soon.
カレー完成？？
Is the curry finished??
完成です！
It's finished!
イェーイ！！やったー！
Yay!! We did it!
味整いました
The flavor is set.
整いました
It's set.
名前はどうします？何カレーです？
What should we name it? What kind of curry is it?
ゲマズの...
The Gamers'...
ゲマズのぶち込みカレー
Gamers' Throw-in Curry.
確かにぶち込みカレーやな
It certainly is a 'throw-in' curry.
実食
Let's Eat
じゃあ食べますか！
Alright, shall we eat!
食べましょうでは
Let's eat, then.
いただきまーす！！
Thanks for the food!!
美味しそう
Looks so good.
ナンだナンだ
It's Naan, it's Naan.
わ〜ナンだナンだ
Wow, it's Naan, it's Naan.
あ、じゃがいもいい感じ
Oh, the potatoes are just right.
本当？
Really?
う〜ん、美味しい！！
Mm, it's delicious!!
具だくさんや
It's so full of ingredients.
いいね
Nice.
けっこうスパイシー
It's quite spicy.
うん、これくらいの辛さちょうどいいかも
Yeah, this level of heat might be just right.
うま〜！
So tasty!
エビの味がすごい
The shrimp flavor is amazing.
エビ見つけた？
Did you find a shrimp?
イカかな？これ
Is this squid?
シーフードか分かんなくて肉かと思って食べたらイカだったっぽい
I couldn't tell it was seafood, thought it was meat but it turned out to be squid.
イカもあれですからね
Squid is also like that.
何が入ってるかわからないこのドキドキ感いいね
This excitement of not knowing what's inside is nice.
初めてカレー作ってみて
Since this was my first time making curry...
楽しかったね
It was fun.
次はひとりで作れるかも！
Maybe I can make it by myself next time!
ミオちゃんにいっぱい研修してもらったからね
Because I got lots of training from Mio-chan.
まあなかなかね、こうやってゲーマーズで集まることもね
Well, gathering like this as Gamers doesn't happen often.
年に一回くらいしかないからね
Since it only happens about once a year.
じゃあお次は来年？
So, is the next time next year?
来年！？
Next year!?
「次は来年だね」っておかゆのライブで言ってたよね
You said 'Next time is next year' at Okayu's live, right?
多いんだよ今年は！
There are a lot of gatherings this year!
多すぎるとちょっとね...！
If there are too many, it's a bit...!
良いことやん多いのは！！
It's a good thing if there are many!!
バランス調整して
To balance it out...
来年は会わないでおこう
...let's not meet next year.
オイッ！！嘘でしょ！？
Hey!! You're kidding, right!?
お腹いっぱいだぁ
I'm so full.
けっこうお腹いっぱいになった
I got quite full.
具だくさんだからね
Because it was full of ingredients.
あ、じゃがいもあった
Oh, I found a potato.
ごっちょおちゃまでした
Thanks for the meal!
うますぎたなこれ
This was way too delicious.
ころね お風呂入ってこようかな？
Korone, maybe I should go take a bath?
お、お風呂？いってらっしゃーい！
Oh, the bath? Have a good soak!
いただいちゃま〜す！
I'm going in!
うわ〜気持ちいい〜！
Wow, this feels great!
わ〜〜！
Waaah!
めっちゃ気持ちいい〜！
It feels so good!
ころね〜！
Korone!
わ〜！！ ころね〜！！
Wah! Korone!
〜一緒に入ろ〜！！
Let's get in together!
みんなで入ると溢れちゃうよ〜
If we all get in, it'll overflow!
うわぁぁぁ!!!!
Whoaaaaa!
このまま寝れるで
I could fall asleep like this.
ここで寝てもいいのかな？
Is it okay to sleep here?
※お風呂で寝るのはやめましょう
*Please do not sleep in the bath.
お肌ツルツルになりそうな感じだぁ
It feels like my skin's going to get so smooth.
もうツルツルだよ 触って
It's already smooth. Feel it.
いや〜んツルツルー！！
Oh my, it's so smooth!
あっやだツルツルぅ〜！！
Ah, stop it, it's so smooth!
タオル準備してくるの忘れたから 一回ちょっと･･･
I forgot to bring a towel, so I'll just head out for a sec...
タオル取りに行こう〜！
Let's go grab the towels!
これって湯足せないの？
Can't we add more hot water?
きゃああああ!!!
Kyaaaaa!
(お湯)出てくる･･･
(The water) is coming out...
ちょっと何すんの!!!
Hey, what are you doing?!
やめてよぉ〜!!
Cut it out!
うおおおい!!!
Whoaaaa!
お前の時もやるぞ!!
I'll do the same to you!
めっちゃ暗いんだけどｗ マジで!!
Seriously, it's pitch black!
マジで暗い!! マジで暗いからな!!
It's really dark!! I mean it!!
覚えとけよ！ ばか
Just you wait! Idiot!
就寝
Going to sleep
さっぱり〜！
So refreshed!
さっぱりしましたね〜！
That was really refreshing!
イチャつくな!!!
Stop flirting!
おかころがずっとイチャついてんだよなぁ
Oka-Koro have been flirting the whole time.
あとでね･･･ 「あとでね」!??
Later... "Later"?!
冗談冗談ｗ
Just kidding!
眠くなったよぉ〜 寝むくなったねぇ〜
I'm getting sleepy. So sleepy.
じゃあ電気消します？
Should we turn off the light?
か〜ら〜の〜 か〜ら〜の〜？？
And theeen? And then what?
「からの」なんだよ!!
"And then" what?!
ちゃんと寝てるか？
Are you actually sleeping?
起きてる
I'm awake.
明日早いもんねぇ 明日も早いからね
We have an early start tomorrow. We do.
オール!! オール!! やべぇ〜
All-nighter!! All-nighter!! Oh boy...
元気なやつおるって〜
Someone's still energetic...
おかゆ! こら!!
Okayu! Hey!!
イチャつき警察だ!!
It's the flirting police!
ぽかぽかだぁ〜･･･
So warm and cozy...
大丈夫? おかゆん 襲われてない?
You okay, Okayun? Not being attacked?
なんか乗っかってるけど 大丈夫
Something's on top of me, but I'm okay.
イチャゴラ警察出るぞ
The flirting police are coming.
イチャこら警察出たなぁ イチャこら警察来るよ?
The flirting police are out. The flirting police are coming?
じゃあ電気つける?
Should I turn on the light?
やめろおおおお!!
Stop it!
ちゃんと寝ます･･･
I'll go to sleep properly...
今日からホロライブは･･･ 「アイドルレスラー」を目指すことになりましたーっ!!
From today, Hololive... will aim to become "Idol Wrestlers"!!
5周年も･･･ ムキムキツネ♡
Even in the 5th year... Muscle Fox!
5周年でも自分らしく･･･
Even in the 5th year, being myself...
マフィア梶田
Mafia Kajita
中村悠一
Yuichi Nakamura
白上フブキ
Fubuki Shirakami
フブキちゃんいらっしゃい!
Welcome, Fubuki-chan!
お邪魔しま〜す!
Thanks for having me!
ついに来てくれたね!
You finally came!
出力先が違うぜ?
Isn't the output destination different?
出力先の登録者数が違うぞ?
The number of subscribers at the output destination is different?
初期からわしゃがなTVを応援してくれている
She's been supporting Wasyagana TV since the beginning.
そうですね！
That's right!
「わ！キタ！」と思って
I thought, "Wow! It's here!!"
メンバーシップにも入らせて頂いて...
I even joined the membership...
メンバーシップにも入らせて頂いて
I even joined the membership
でも聞いたところによると
But from what I've heard,
フブキちゃんは元々中村悠一のファン...
Fubuki-chan was originally a fan of Yuichi Nakamura...
中村悠一のファン
A fan of Yuichi Nakamura
あー、そうですね... はい。
Ah, that's right... yes.
そうですね…
That's right...
大体そうなの。ファンの人はそれ以上語ってくれない。
It's usually like that. Fans don't say anything more than that.
大体そうなの
It's usually like that
ファンの人はそれ以上語ってくれない
Fans don't say anything more than that
いや、なんかもう...
No, well...
いつもそうなの。
It's always like that.
いつもそうなの
It's always like that
いつももう慣れっこですよ。
I'm used to it by now.
いつももう慣れっこですよ
I'm used to it by now
「あーそうなんですよ！」
"Oh, that's right!"
...で止まります。
...and they stop there.
…（沈黙）
...(Silence)
いや、さすがにその、ご本人様を目の前にして
No, as expected, facing the person themselves...
御本人様を目の前にして
Facing the person themselves
そういうあの限界を迎えで良いのかってのが本当に...
I wonder if it's okay to reach that kind of limit...
限界を迎えて良いのか？
Is it okay to reach the limit?
良いんだよ！
It's fine!
良いんですか！？
Is it really fine!?
良いんだよ。
It's fine.
中村悠一さんがおるぅ〜！
Yuichi Nakamura is here~!
中村悠一さんがおるぅ↑
Yuichi Nakamura is here!
ほんとにいらっしゃるっ！
He's really here!
ほんとにいらっしゃるッ！
ま、そうなったらそうなったで、やっぱやりづらいから。
Well, if that happens, it's hard to deal with.
やっぱりづらいから
Because it's hard to deal with after all
はい、そういうことで。
Yes, so anyway.
今日はね、我々の事をもっと知ってもらおうと思って
Today, to let you know more about us,
今日はね
Today
私物紹介。
Personal items introduction.
私物紹介
Personal items introduction
お！
Oh!
よくやるじゃない。
We do that often.
やってますね、やってらっしゃいますね。
We do, we do.
我々の人となりを知る上でもね
To understand our personality too,
うん。
Yeah.
非常に役立つ企画なんだけれども
It's a very useful project,
確かに。
True.
今回はね、また色々持ってきたんで
This time, I brought various things,
私物紹介からお届けしていこうかなあと思います。
I think we'll start with the introduction of personal items.
やってくか。
Let's do it.
じゃ、中村さんからお願いします。
Well, let's start with Nakamura-san.
中村さんからお願いします
Nakamura-san, please
俺から。
From me.
中村さんから！はい。
From Nakamura-san! Yes.
なるほど。こちらなんですけども。
I see. It's this one.
ほう。
Ho.
なんですか。
What is it.
ブルガリ！？
BVLGARI!?
「BVLGARI」！？
ブルガリ。香水なら持ってるけどな。
BVLGARI. I have the perfume, though.
これがですね、えーとですね。
This is, uh...
はー、厳重に。
Wow, it's secure.
腕...
Wrist...
あらららら。
Oh, oh, oh.
腕時計。
Wristwatch.
腕時計！
Wristwatch!
腕時計
Wristwatch
あ〜らヤダ！いやらしい！
Oh, no! How scandalous!
あぁ～らヤダ
Oh, no
いやらしい！！
How scandalous!!
も〜何ですか、ブルガリの腕時計って。
What's this, a BVLGARI watch?
そうでしょ。これが、あの...
Right. This is, you know...
自分が30歳になった時に
When I turned 30,
When I turned 30
ちょっと、頑張った価格の物を買おうと思った...
I decided to buy something at a price I had to push myself for...
頑張った価格の物を買おうと思った
I decided to buy something at a price I had to push myself for
ああ、記念にね。
Ah, as a memento.
記念に。13年前。
As a memento. 13 years ago.
13年前。
13 years ago.
13年前に買った時計、1年で壊れました。
The watch I bought 13 years ago, it broke in one year.
1年で壊れました
It broke in one year
えっ！？
Eh!?
なぜかと言うと、ハードユースなんですよ。
The reason is hard use.
ハードユースなんですよ
It's hard use
え、めちゃめちゃ使ったんですか？
What, did you use it that much?
あとで気づいたんですけど、こういう時計、ハードに使わない。
I realized later, you don't use this kind of watch harshly.
こういう時計ハードに使わない
You don't use this kind of watch harshly
使わない、使わない。
You don't, you don't.
ああ。
Ah.
そうでしょ。もう常に、どこ行くにもコイツと一緒だから。
Right. Always, wherever I go, I'm with this guy.
どこ行くにもコイツと一緒
Wherever I go, I'm with this guy
常にコイツと一緒。
Always with this guy.
1ヶ月後ぐらいに、見たら分かるんだけど
About a month later, you can tell by looking at it,
あの、めっちゃ傷だらけなんだよ。
Uh, it's full of scratches.
めっちゃ傷だらけなんだよ
It's full of scratches
そりゃそうですわ。もう擦れまくってるから。
That's expected. It's getting rubbed all over.
そりゃそうですわ。それにその時計の形状ね。
That's expected. And that watch's shape...
腕に沿うように丸型になってますもんね。
It's round-shaped to fit the wrist, isn't it.
あ、本当ですね。
Ah, you're right.
あ、結構やれてますね。
Oh, it's quite worn.
新人の時には、マネージャーに言われたの。
When I was a newcomer, my manager told me.
ペンと時計と靴は頑張って良いものをつけろって
Try hard and wear a good pen, watch, and shoes
言われたんですか。
He told you?
ペンと時計と靴は頑張って良いものをつけろって。
To try hard and wear a good pen, watch, and shoes.
なるほど。
I see.
言われましたけどね。
I was told that.
何でかって言うと、アニメの現場だと関係ないんだけど
The reason is, it doesn't matter at anime recording sites,
ナレーションの現場とか行くと、やっぱりそこで
But when you go to narration sites, after all...
まあ、汚い話だけど稼いでいるかどうかを見る。
Well, it's a dirty topic, but they look at whether you're earning money.
稼いでいるかどうかを見る
Look at whether you're earning money
＝仕事をしてる人かどうかを見るから。
Because they see whether you're someone who is working.
＝仕事をしてる人かどうか
= Whether you're someone who is working
あああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
そうそう。どう思った？フブちゃん。
Right, right. What did you think, Fubu-chan?
どう思った？フブちゃん
What did you think, Fubu-chan?
いや、いいですね、やっぱ時計。
Well, it's great, after all, a watch.
時計
Watch
時計持ってらっしゃるの想像して、今、ああ、いいな、と。
Imagining you wearing a watch now, ah, that's nice.
あぁ～良いな…
Ah, that's nice...
お前、全肯定だな。
You're totally affirmative.
お前全肯定だな
You're totally affirmative
全肯定です！エピソードとか中村悠一さんにも。
Totally affirmative! Also for the episodes and Nakamura-san.
俺に有利に進むぞ、全部が全部肯定されるじゃない。
It's going in my favor; everything is being affirmed.
俺に有利に進むぞ
It's going in my favor
全肯定オタクなんで！
I'm a totally affirmative otaku!
今だと本当に中村悠一さん、アニメとかゲームとか色んなところで見るんですけども
Nowadays, I really see Yuichi Nakamura in anime, games, and various places,
やっぱりその新人の頃を想像して、ああ、いいな、っていう。
But imagining his rookie days, ah, that's nice.
新人の頃を想像して
Imagining his rookie days
あぁ～良いな…
Ah, that's nice...
ああ、新人の頃の中村さん。
Ah, Nakamura-san in his rookie days.
新人の頃の中村悠一さん、可愛かったんだろうなあって。
Yuichi Nakamura in his rookie days must have been cute.
可愛かったんだろうなあって？
He must have been cute?
でしょうねえ〜！！
I'm sure he was~!!
でしょうね〜！！
こやつのオタク仕草は極まっとる！
This person's otaku behavior is at its peak!
こやつのオタク仕草は
This person's otaku behavior
極まっとる！
Is at its peak!
いやいや、なかなか聞けないエピソードが聞けましたよ。
No, no, we got to hear a rare episode.
そうですね、聞けてよかったです。ありがとうございます。
Yes, I'm glad I could hear it. Thank you.
じゃあ、ちょっと方向性間違えたかな？
Well, did I get the direction wrong?
方向性間違えたかな？
Did I get the direction wrong?
方向性。
Direction.
なんかね、せっかくフブちゃん来るから
Since Fubu-chan is coming here,
フブちゃんにプレゼントも兼ねて私物紹介をする
I thought I'd do the personal items introduction as a gift for Fubu-chan too,
っていう風に思ってたんよ、俺は。
That's what I was thinking.
んで、だから色々持ってきたんだけど、もうこれ全部君にあげる前提で
So, I brought various things, assuming I'll give them all to you.
もうこれ全部君にあげる
I'll give them all to you
え、全部！？
Eh, all of them!?
今のラインナップ持って来た。
I brought the current lineup.
いや、ちゃんと言葉の裏を取って。
No, take the meaning behind the words.
言葉の裏を取ると「逃げれないよ」って事。
If you take the meaning behind the words, it means "you can't escape."
「逃げれないよ」って事
It means "you can't escape"
あ、そういう事！？
Ah, is that so!?
いや、そんなことない。
No, that's not it.
嫌な予感。
I have a bad feeling.
まずはこちら。
First, this one.
なんですか？お、黒い箱。
What is it? Oh, a black box.
オンスライス。
ON SLICE.
[ON SLICE]
オンスライス。
ON SLICE.
よく分かりません。オンスライスは。
I don't really know. About ON SLICE.
よく分かりません
I don't really know
じゃあ何で紹介したんだよ。
Then why did you introduce it?
じゃあなんで紹介したんだよ
Then why did you introduce it
なぜなら、あの俺はサングラス集めるの趣味だって言ったじゃないですか。
Because, I told you that collecting sunglasses is my hobby, didn't I?
うん。
Yeah.
これもサングラスなんですけど。
This is also a pair of sunglasses.
だと思った。
I thought so.
ただ、Instagramって見ます？たまに。
But, do you look at Instagram? Sometimes.
見ます、見ます。
I do, I do.
インスタ見てると
When I'm looking at Instagram
インスタ見てるとたまに広告入りませんか？
Don't you occasionally see ads when you're looking at Instagram?
入ります！
I do!
そこでサングラス売ってたんですよ。
Sunglasses were being sold there.
ほう。
Ho.
Instagramで買い物したことねえなと思って
I thought, I've never shopped on Instagram before,
そっから飛んで買ってみたんです。
So I jumped from there and bought them.
ほう。
Ho.
そしたらね...
And then...
おお〜。
Ooh~.
赤い！
Red!
赤いし
Red, and
赤いですね。
They're red, aren't they.
赤いし、バネついてんのよ。
They're red, and they have springs.
バネついてんのよ
It has springs
その赤いのはヘルシングぐらいしか見たことないですよ。
I've only seen that red in Hellsing.
ちなみに今俺がかけてんのがヘルシングモデルなんだけれども。
By the way, the ones I'm wearing now are the Hellsing model.
そうですよね。赤、似てる。
That's right. Red, they're similar.
本当だ。これはこれでデザインが面白いなと思って買ったんだけれども
You're right. I bought these because I thought the design was interesting, but...
なんかね、薄いんだよね。
Somehow, they're thin.
薄いんだよね
They're thin
薄いね。うん。
They're thin. Yeah.
なんか色が薄いんだよね。
Somehow the color is thin.
薄いですね。
It's thin.
多分君みたいな人がかけない想定なんじゃない？
Maybe they're not intended for someone like you to wear?
君みたいな人がかけない想定
Not intended for someone like you to wear
で、調べてみたらなんかね、ちょっとおしゃれめな女優さんとかがかけてて。
So I looked it up, and apparently, some stylish actresses were wearing them.
そういう事ですよ。
That's how it is.
ああ、そういう。
Ah, I see.
これ俺じゃねえなと思って買ったはいいけどずっとつけてなかったんですよ。
I thought, "This isn't for me," so I bought them but never wore them.
ということで、これは君の新衣装だ。
So, this is your new outfit.
君の新衣装だ
Your new outfit
新衣装、新アイテム！なるほど。
New outfit, new item! I see.
ただね、これだけだとやっぱりグラサンだけじゃわかんないかなって
But, just with these sunglasses, I wonder if you won't get it.
グラサンだけじゃ
Just with these sunglasses
全体トータルコーディネートが。
The overall total coordination.
わかんないかな？
I wonder if you won't get it
おお、なるほど。
Oh, I see.
見えてきましたよ、この流れ。
I can see it now, this flow.
はい、こちら。
Yes, here.
I RIDE SO I DON'T CHOKE PEOPLE.
どういう意味ですか？
What does that mean?
「俺はバイクに乗ってるから人の首を締めずに済んでんだぜ」
"Since I'm riding a bike, I don't have to choke people's necks."
これを着るんだよお前が。
You're going to wear this.
えっ！？ これ新衣装なんですか！？
Eh!? Is this my new outfit!?
マフィア梶田なりきりセットってことで？
So it's a Mafia Kajita cosplay set?
一点思ったのが、エピソードないよね？
One thing I thought was, there's no story behind it, right?
この二点にあなたのエピソード存在してませんよね。
正直俺は着ないかな。
Your own story doesn't exist for these two items.
Honestly, I probably won't wear these.
白上さんにあげるためだけに用意してる。
You prepared them just to give to Shirakami-san.
まだ精度を上げる道具がひとつある。
There's one more tool to increase the precision.
こちらの Glock です。
It's this Glock.
あっでも Glock はちょっと嬉しいかもしれないです！
Ah, but I might be a little happy about a Glock!
こちら Glock 17、プレゼントいたします。
I'll gift you this Glock 17.
お前チャカ持ち歩いてんの？
Are you carrying a gun around?
一応アイドルなんですけど...
I'm technically an idol, but...
まあここまでの流れはね、全部茶番ということで。
Well, the flow up to this point has all been a farce.
あるんですよ、モノホンがね。我々用意したやつが。
We have it, the real thing. Something we prepared.
出しますかもう？ そこに俺っちがいるから出して。
Shall we show it now? It's right there, so take it out.
こちら！ 白上フブキ×わしゃがな♪
5周年おめでとう！
This! Shirakami Fubuki x Washagana♪
Congratulations on your 5th anniversary!
ありがとうございます！！ え、待ってください、サイン入ってる！
Thank you very much!! Wait, it has signatures!
プレゼントするっても何がいいのかが全くわからなくて。
Even if we were to gift something, we had no idea what would be good.
普通の私物だと今のラインナップになっちゃうし。
If it's just regular personal items, it ends up like the previous lineup.
その BVLGARI くれるんでしょ？
You're giving that Bvlgari, right?
なんでや！
Why would I!?
コラボしたことも思い出に残りつつってことで、
大川先生に相談して描いてもらったらですね...
To have a memory of this collaboration,
I consulted with Okawa-sensei and had him draw it...
ちょっと一点問題がありまして。
僕らのサインを書くスペースを考えてくれてなかった。
But there's one problem.
He didn't leave any space for our signatures.
一切ない。だからちょっとこの当て付けたような書き方になってる。
中村さんマイク・タイソンみたいになってる。
None at all. So it's written in this cramped way.
Nakamura-san looks like Mike Tyson.
でもまあこれね、この世に一枚だから、ぜひ大事にしてもらえると。
But well, this is one of a kind in the world, so please treasure it.
大事にさせて頂きます！ ありがとうございます！！
I will treasure it! Thank you very much!!
飾ります！ 神棚があるのでそこに一度捧げておこうと思います。
I will! I have an altar, so I'll offer it there once.
この4点セットで。 / 4点セットで！ わかりました！
With this 4-piece set. / 4-piece set! I understand!
（私物）持って来てんの？
Did you bring a personal item?
はい！ ちょっとだけお話をさせて頂きたいなと。
出しちゃって頂いてもいいですか？
Yes! I have something I'd like to talk about for a bit.
Is it okay if I bring it out?
こちらは FFXIV のオーケストラコンサートで販売されました
「エルピスの花」というお花でございます。
This is the "Elpis Flower" that was sold at the
FFXIV orchestra concert.
ゲーム中に出てくる設定的に大事なアイテムなんだけど。
It's an item that's important setting-wise in the game.
パクリてぇよな？ / パクリてぇ！ この企画な？
Don't you want to steal it? / I want to steal it! This project, right?
ホロライブ内にもプレイヤーの子がいて、
その子と一緒に実はコンサートに行かせて頂きまして。
Actually, there's another player in Hololive,
and I went to the concert with her.
愛のあふれるコンサートだったなということで、
思い出の品として持ってきました。
It was a concert full of love,
so I brought it as a memento.
明かりつくの？ どうやってつけるの？ / あっ、つきます。
お花の下のところにボタンがあると思うんですけど。
Does it light up? How do you turn it on? / Ah, it does.
I think there's a button at the bottom of the flower.
曲中の途中で一斉につけてくださいっていうシーンがあるんですよ。
一斉にお花が咲くっていう。
There's a scene during a song where they ask everyone to turn
them on at once. It's like the flowers bloom all at once.
ゲーム本編にもそういう演出がありまして、はい。
There's a similar production in the main game too.
ホロライブのメンバーと一緒に行けたというのがまた思い出深くて。
Being able to go with a Hololive member made it even more memorable.
俺らも入れてくんね？ 事務所。
Can you let us join too? The agency.
ホロスターズとして！
As Holostars!
ファンサとか出来ますか？ / ファンサ普段からやっとるやっとる！
Can we do fan service? / We've been doing fan service normally!
ファンサって何？ トマトぶつけるんだっけ？
/ 何処の国のファンサっすか！？ 何処の祭りですか！？
What's fan service? Throwing tomatoes?
/ What country's fan service is that!? What festival is that!?
最近指ハートとかも流行ってますし。
Finger hearts have been popular lately too.
￥マニーマニーマニー
Money, money, money.
違います！！ お札を弾いてる指だと思い込んで...
/ アイドルがずっとお札をこう...
No!! You think it's fingers flicking bills...
/ An idol constantly doing this with bills...
この動画どこで出るかちゃんと理解してる？ 200万人が観とるぞ。
Do you understand where this video is going to be released?
Two million people are watching.
ちょっと待て、俺一つ恐ろしいことに気付いたんだけど、時間が...
Wait, I just realized something terrifying... the time...
フブキちゃんからプレゼントがあるそうです！！
There's supposedly a gift from Fubuki-chan!!
こちら、白上が80万人記念の時に出しましたオリジナルTシャツです。
These are the original T-shirts Shirakami released for
her 800k milestone.
狐と狼の、スカーフを使ってるんですけど。
It's a fox and a wolf wearing scarves.
ちょっと私が今着てる衣装が違うんですけど、
It's slightly different from my current outfit,
おお、カッコいいカッコいい。
Oh, it's very cool.
はい、狐と王冠とスカーフで。
Yes, with the fox, crown, and scarf.
キャラクター物っぽくない感じで、
I wanted it to not look too much like 'character merch',
普段でも着れるようなことをイメージして。
so I designed it to be wearable in daily life.
着る機会ございましたら、着ていただければ幸いです。
If you have the chance, I'd be happy if you wore it.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
うわぁ！では続いていきましょうか。
Wow! Well then, shall we move on?
あと５...３分くらいで！
Only about 5... 3 minutes left!
あと３分で閉まる！
We're ending in three minutes!
３分！？出来るか！？
Three minutes!? Can we do it!?
え、じゃあこちらが開封するんですけども、
Well then, I'll be unboxing this...
ホロライブ はぐみーつ スタンドミニアクリルキーホルダー。
Hololive Hug-me Stand Mini Acrylic Key Holder.
あ、可愛い！こちらです。
Oh, cute! Here it is.
右上に今回一期生と、ホロライブEnglish -Myth- という、
On the top right, we have the 1st Gen and Hololive English -Myth-...
英語圏のメンバーのラインナップとなっております。
...English-speaking members in the lineup.
おお、なるほどなるほど。
Oh, I see, I see.
中村悠一に箱の開封は任せるとして。
We'll leave the unboxing to Nakamura Yuichi.
箱は絶対に綺麗に開けないと気が済まない男だから。
He's a man who has to open boxes perfectly.
じゃあ奥の方から引いていきましょうかね。
Let's draw from the back then.
じゃあ私行きますよ。
Alright, I'm going.
はい、お願いします。お一人目が...
Yes, please. The first person is...
1人目 夜空メルちゃんです！
The 1st one is Mel Yozora-chan!
夜空メルちゃんは私と同じホロライブ一期生のメンバーで、
Mel Yozora-chan is a member of Hololive 1st Gen like me,
魔界の天才ヴァンパイアなんです。
and she's a genius vampire from the demon world.
ヴァンパイアなのか。そうです、ヴァンパイアなんです。
She's a vampire. Yes, she is.
これなんか、その「キャラ被り」って言い方...
Is there anything like 'character overlap'...
同族の方とかいるんですか？
...with others of the same kind?
ヴァンパイアの方は他にも？
Are there other vampires?
ホロライブ内にはいないんですけど、VTuberいろんな方がいるので、
Not within Hololive, but since there are many Vtubers out there,
もちろんヴァンパイアの方々も沢山いらっしゃいますね。
of course, there are plenty of other vampires.
思いつくだけで4、5人はいるかもしれない。
Just off the top of my head, there might be 4 or 5.
あ、そうなんだ。やっぱ人気なんだね。
Ah, I see. They really are popular.
じゃあ次の子いきましょうか。はい！次々。
Shall we go for the next one? Yes! Next, next.
2人目 赤井はあとちゃんですね。
The 2nd one is Haato Akai-chan.
はあとちゃんもホロライブ一期生の女の子でして、
Haato-chan is also a Hololive 1st Gen girl,
蜘蛛とかを食べた実績がございます。
and she has a record of eating spiders.
蜘蛛食べた！？
She ate a spider!?
はい。タランチュラとかを配信内で食べたことがある...
Yes. She's eaten things like tarantulas on stream.
頼まれて？
By request?
いや、もう自ら進んで。
No, she did it of her own accord.
やるねぇ！はあちゃまクッキングというもので...
She's hardcore! It's for Haachama Cooking...
クソっ... 負けてたぁ！
Damn... I lost!
うちまだやってないから、蜘蛛食うの。
We haven't done that yet, eating spiders.
古いレーションと古いビックリマンしか食ってない。
I've only eaten old rations and old Bikkuriman.
一緒に食べたりは？
Did you eat them together?
デビューしたての頃に、虫は食べたことありました。
Right around my debut, I did eat some bugs.
マジで！？はい、興味本位で。
Seriously!? Yes, out of curiosity.
やっぱりホロライブ入りません。
I'm definitely not joining Hololive.
あ！なんで！？僕たちは入りません。
Ah! Why!? We're not joining.
登竜門が虫じゃないですから！大丈夫ですよ！
The gateway isn't bugs! It's okay!
新人はまずこれいける？ってタランチュラ出されて。
Asking newcomers 'Can you handle this?' and serving a tarantula.
俺まだ頑張れるかも。梶田さん、じゃあ残って。
I might still be able to handle it. Kajita, you stay then.
俺まだ心いけるかも。まだまだ粘る粘る。
My heart might still be in it. I'll stick it out.
そんなことないです、そんなことないです。
That's not how it is, not at all.
じゃあ次いきましょう。えーっと...
Let's go for the next one. Let's see...
3人目 がうる・ぐらちゃんですね。
The 3rd one is Gawr Gura-chan.
ぐらちゃんは海外圏のMythのメンバーでサメなんです。
Gura-chan is a member of the overseas branch Myth, and she's a shark.
サメちゃんです。デビュー配信の時に...
She's a shark-chan. In her debut stream...
画面に出てきて一言目が「a」だったんですよね。
the first thing she said when she appeared was 'a'.
もうそれですごい、海外の方でバズりにバズりまして。
With just that, she went incredibly viral overseas.
そうなんです。最初の一言が「a」。
That's right. Her very first word was 'a'.
俺知ってるなぁ、この子。
I know her.
あ！知ってますか？がうる・ぐらちゃんだ。
Oh! You know her? It's Gawr Gura-chan.
日本語もすごく上手くて、たまに話してくれたりします。
She's also very good at Japanese and speaks it sometimes.
サメ族もいるなぁ。サメってコンテンツが人気だもんね。
There's a shark kind too. Sharks are popular content after all.
意外と出ないんですね、フブキさん。出ないですね。
Surprisingly, Fubuki-san isn't coming out. I'm not.
4人目 小鳥遊キアラちゃんですね。
The 4th one is Kiara Takanashi-chan.
キアラちゃんもぐらちゃんと同じグループで、不死鳥なんですよ。
Kiara-chan is in the same group as Gura-chan, and she's a phoenix.
不死鳥？はい、不死鳥なんです。
A phoenix? Yes, she is.
火の鳥かい？そうなんです。
The Firebird? That's right.
チキンがすごく大好きと言いますか...
She loves chicken, or should I say...
火の鳥なのにチキンが好き？はい、KFPということで。
A Firebird who likes chicken? Yes, as in KFP.
今度聞いといて。「火の鳥」では何編が好きか。
Ask her next time which chapter of 'Phoenix' she likes.
そこからとってないと思うんですよね。そこからじゃない？
I don't think it's from that. Not from that?
手塚先生じゃないと思うんですけど、聞いておきます。
I don't think it's Tezuka-sensei's, but I'll ask.
5人目 夏色まつりちゃんです。
The 5th one is Matsuri Natsuiro-chan.
この子も私と同じホロライブ一期生で、チアリーダーをやってます。
She's also Hololive 1st Gen like me, and she's a cheerleader.
歌とダンスが一番やっぱりすごく可愛くて。
Her singing and dancing are really the cutest after all.
夏色フブキというコンビで、コラボしたりしてます。
We collab as a duo called Natsuiro Fubuki.
応援してほしいねぇ。超応援してほしい。
I want her to cheer for me. I really do.
チアリーディングしてほしい。感想が若干おっさん染みてる。
I want some cheerleading. You sound like a middle-aged man.
おっさんなんだからしょうがないでしょう。確かにそうだけど。
I am a middle-aged man, so what do you expect? True.
俺も流石に思いつかない。「ねぇ、応援してほしいねぇ」って。
Even I wouldn't think of that. 'Man, I want her to cheer for me.'
多分コメント欄そういうので溢れてると思うよ。あ、応援！
Probably the comments are full of that. Ah, cheering!
「応援してほしい」って。俺も、私も。
'I want her to cheer for me.' 'Me too.'
だってみんな疲れてんだもん、おっさんは。
Because all us middle-aged men are tired.
やめろやめろ。はい、続きまして。
Stop it. Okay, moving on.
6人目 ワトソン・アメリアちゃん。探偵ですね。
The 6th one is Amelia Watson. She's a detective.
探偵なんです。職業シリーズもあるんだね。
She's a detective. There's a profession series too.
ホームズ帽だ。相当頭いいんかい？
A Holmes cap. Is she incredibly smart?
あ、どうも…
Oh, hello...
どうなんですかね…
I wonder...
そこは疑問なんかい
You're doubting that?!
ちょっとPONなところがあったりもしますけど
I do have my clumsy moments sometimes, but...
ちょっとPONなところがある
She has some clumsy moments.
探偵味を感じる部分はあのあるの？
Is there anything about her that feels like a detective?
あー、ありますね…
Ah, there is...
なさそうだよ？
Doesn't seem like it.
7枚目 白上フブキ
7th: Shirakami Fubuki
あ、当たり。当たりが出ちゃった。
Ah, the "win". I pulled the winner.
きました！あー、出た！ありがとうございます！
Here it is! Ah, she's out! Thank you very much!
はい、白上フブキでございます。
Yes, it's Shirakami Fubuki.
この子はどんな子なんだい？
What kind of girl is she?
この子はですね…
This girl...
わしゃがなを毎週見逃さずに…
Well, she never misses a week of Washagana...
おお。
Oh.
アラートをしっかりかけておりまして。
She sets alerts for every episode.
えらいね。
That's good.
ツイートを見かけたらRTして見ようねと、
When she sees a tweet, she retweets it and says "Let's watch".
いそいそ布教をしているキツネですね。
She's a fox who's diligently spreading the word.
なんて素晴らしい子なんだ、これ。
What a wonderful girl she is.
俺これから推すよ！
I'm going to support her from now on!
ありがとうございます！ぜひともよろしくお願いします。
Thank you! Please do.
初めて知ったけどこれから推す。
Just found out about her, but I'm a fan now.
フブキちゃんっていうのかあ！すごいね。
So her name is Fubuki! Amazing.
チェックしていくよ！
We'll be checking her out!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
8枚目 アキ・ローゼンタール
8th: Aki Rosenthal
アキさん。
Aki-san.
あ、アキ・ローゼンタールちゃんですね。
Ah, it's Aki Rosenthal-chan.
ローゼンタール。
Rosenthal.
はい、アキちゃんも1期生で同じなんですけど、
Yes, Aki-chan is also from the 1st generation like me...
ハーフエルフなんですよ、この子は。
And she's a half-elf.
ハーフエルフ。
Half-elf.
そうなんです、ハーフエルフなんです。
That's right, she's a half-elf.
ベリーダンスがすごい得意な子なんです。
She's very good at belly dancing.
ベリーダンス。
Belly dancing.
はい、ベリーダンス。
Yes, belly dancing.
珍しいね。
That's unusual.
そうなんです。なので楽曲も結構そのアラビアン的な…
It is. So her songs are also quite Arabian-style...
民族チックな中でちょっと妖艶に踊っていくという。
She dances enchantingly to ethnic-style tunes.
おもしろい。
Interesting.
そうなんです。
Exactly.
ハーフエルフのベリーダンス見たことねえ俺。
I've never seen a half-elf belly dance before.
あー、ぜひとも見ていただきたい。
Ah, I'd definitely love for you to see it.
俺もねえし。
Me neither.
みんなねえよ。
Nobody has.
基本的にはね。
Normally, no.
次。イナニスちゃんかな？
Next. Is it Ina'nis-chan?
9枚目 一伊那尓栖
9th: Ninomae Ina'nis
はい、一伊那尓栖ちゃんです。
Yes, it's Ninomae Ina'nis-chan.
イナニスちゃんはいわゆるこう…邪神って言っていいんでしょうかね？
Ina'nis-chan is, well... can I call her an Outer God?
知ってる？
Do you know?
知ってる。
I know.
知ってんの？
You do?
知ってますか！そうなんです、タコなんです。
You know her?! That's right, she's an octopus.
タコ。
Octopus.
おお。
Oh.
冒涜的な。
Blasphemous.
そう、ちょっと冒涜的なんですけども、
Yes, a bit blasphemous, but...
声が本当に可愛くて！透き通ってて。
Her voice is just so cute! And clear.
あと、絵がすごく上手いんですよ。
And she's really good at drawing.
イラストがめちゃめちゃ上手で。
Her illustrations are amazing.
じゃ、これラストです。
Okay, this is the last one.
はい。
Okay.
10枚目 森カリオペ
10th: Mori Calliope
あ、カリオペちゃん！森カリオペちゃんですね。
Ah, Calliope-chan! It's Mori Calliope-chan.
カリオペ。
Calliope.
この子はもう、ラップがとにかくすごいです。
This girl, her rapping is just incredible.
ラップ。
Rap.
ラッパーなんですよ。
She's a rapper.
ラッパーなのか。
A rapper, huh?
はい。もう本当にいろんな有名な方とコラボしたりとか、
Yes. She collabs with all sorts of famous people...
LIVEとかもしてまして、
And she does live performances too.
ぜひラッパーの方は聴いていただきたい。
Rappers should definitely give her a listen.
Lotus Juiceに勧めとくわ。
I'll recommend her to Lotus Juice.
ぜひぜひぜひ！お願いします。
Please do! Yes, please.
お互い知ってるかもしんないけど。
They might already know each other.
知ってっかもな。
Maybe so.
もうバトル済みかもしんない。
They might have even battled already.
まさか。
No way.
バトルして…
Battled...
この子は人間なのかい？
Is she human?
この子は死神なんです。
She's a reaper.
死神！
A reaper!
はい。なんで、デビューの最初に作った曲が、
Yes. That's why the first song she made for her debut...
「失礼しますが、RIP♡」っていう…
Was "Excuse My Rudeness, But Could You Please RIP?".
「失礼しますが死んでください」っていう。
Basically, "Excuse me, but please die".
「失礼しますが Rest In Peace」
Excuse my rudeness, Rest In Peace.
そうなんです。よければ聴いてみてください。
Exactly. Please check it out if you can.
めちゃくちゃイカした曲名じゃねえかよ。
That's a hell of a cool song title.
そうなんです。もう本当にかっこいいラップなので。
It is. Her rapping is really cool.
君は同僚の紹介が上手いな。
You're very good at introducing your colleagues.
あ、いえいえ。
Oh, no...
プレゼン能力が興味深い。
Your presentation skills are impressive.
ありがとうございます。ホロライブのメンバー大好きなので。
Thank you. I love the Hololive members so much.
こうやって紹介できて嬉しいです！
So I'm happy to be able to introduce them like this!
これで全部っすか？
Is that all of them?
これで全部です。
This is all of them.
これで、はい、出てるものは全部紹介させていただきました。
Yes, these are all the ones currently available that I've introduced.
はい、ありがとうございました！
Alright, thank you very much!
さあ、ここであれですね。
Now then, here we have...
フブキさんからお知らせ。
A notice from Fubuki.
フブキさんからお知らせ
Notice from Fubuki
お知らせ。
A notice.
はい、ちょっとお知らせがあります！
Yes, I have a bit of news!
なんとですね、今回白上フブキ5周年ということで…
Well, as it's Shirakami Fubuki's 5th anniversary...
白上フブキ 5周年
Shirakami Fubuki 5th Anniversary
グッズが出ます！
We're releasing some goods!
そのグッズがこちら！
And here they are!
はい、こちらです！
Yes, here it is!
B2タペストリー
B2 Tapestry
こちらですね、B2のタペストリーで、
This is a B2 tapestry...
緋原ヨウ先生描き下ろしの、ちょっと温泉に入っているタペストリーでございます。
Featuring an original illustration by Yoh Hihara-sensei, of me in an onsen.
このわしゃがなの1個前が、実はホロライブゲーマーズというメンバーで、
Just before Washagana, actually, with the Hololive Gamers members...
温泉に行ったという。
We went to an onsen.
おお。
Oh.
はい。ことで、ちょっとそれをイメージして作っていただきました。
Yes. So we had this made with that in mind.
そして、もう一つこちら！
And another one here!
こちら、せんちゃ先生描き下ろしの、アクリルジオラマスタンドです。
This is an acrylic diorama stand, with an illustration by Sencha-sensei.
アクリルジオラマスタンド
Acrylic Diorama Stand
こちらもね、ちょっと宿でみんなでゆっくりしているというイメージで。
This one is also based on the idea of everyone relaxing at the inn.
めちゃめちゃ酒飲んでるじゃん。
They're drinking a lot of alcohol.
そうなんです。
They are.
めちゃめちゃビール飲んでる。
Drinking a lot of beer.
ビールをちょっと、はい。みんなで乾杯しようかと。
A bit of beer, yes. We're all having a toast.
ああ、いい。かわいい。
Ah, nice. Cute.
こちらです。
Here it is.
そして続いてこちら！
And moving on to this!
こちらはアイマスクです！
This is an eye mask!
こちら白上のオリジナルキャラクター、オリジナルマスコットで、
This is based on my original character, or original mascot...
アイマスク
Eye Mask
「見てる」っていうキャラクターがいるんですけども、
A character called "Miteru" (Watching).
その「見てる」のアイマスクでございます。
It's a "Miteru" eye mask.
ちょっとこちら実物が、お手元にあると思うんですけども。
I believe you have the actual item there with you.
お前を見ているだ
I'm watching you
お前を見ているぞ。
I'm watching you.
そうです。まさにそんなキャラです。
Exactly. That's exactly the kind of character it is.
物陰から…ありがとうございます。
From the shadows... Thank you.
わー！中村悠一さんが付けてるー！
Wow! Nakamura Yuichi-san is wearing it!
俺たちがお前を見ているぞ。
We are watching you.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
これいいなあ。
This is good.
ちょっとそれを、ファンの皆さんにも付けていただいて、
I'd like the fans to wear it too...
ライブとかいろいろ…
At lives and such...
おでこに付けてもネコ耳みたいでね。
Even if you put it on your forehead, it's like cat ears.
確かに。そうですね、キツネ耳みたいで。
True. Yes, like fox ears.
かわいいじゃん、これ。
It's cute, isn't it?
そしてこちらです。
And here's this.
こちらレザーモーテルキーホルダーですね。
This is a leather motel key holder.
今回温泉とか宿とか出てるので、モーテルキーホルダーで。
Since we've been talking about onsens and inns, a motel key holder.
レザーモーテルキーホルダー
Leather Motel Key Holder
みんな付けてほしいなという。
I hope everyone will use it.
フブキハウスに入っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay to enter Fubuki House?
そうです。フブキハウスにちょっとご招待用、っていう。
That's right. It's like an invitation to Fubuki House.
この1005っていうのは？
What's this 1005?
は、10月5日が実は私の誕生日でして。
Well, October 5th is actually my birthday.
おお。
Oh.
ちょっとそれの部屋番号っていう。
So it's like a room number.
こちらのレザーモーテルキーホルダー、ナンバーも入れていただきました。
Here's the leather motel keyholder. They even put the number on it.
はい、こちら、活動5周年記念フルセット、
Yes, and here is the 5th Anniversary Activity Full Set.
フルセット購入特典がございます。数量限定で、白上フブキ直筆サイン＆
There's a bonus for purchasing the full set. In limited quantities,
箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード。通常版は複製サインとメッセージ入りです。
a postcard with Shirakami Fubuki's hand-written signature and foil-stamped message.
参考にします。
I'll keep that in mind.
これ色々使えそうな感じですね。
It feels like we could use this for various things.
本当ですか？直筆サイン入りも沢山の方々が買ってくださるので、
Really? Since many people buy the ones with hand-written signatures,
仕事の合間とかに直筆でキュキュキュっと書いております。
I'm busy signing them "scribble-scribble" during breaks at work.
うちはね、ノウハウを吸収するタイプの番組だから。
Our show is the type that "absorbs" know-how, you see.
あ、本当に！？
Oh, really!?
わかりやすく言うと「パクる」っていう。
To put it simply, it's called "stealing."
えっ！わしゃがなTVさんでやって頂けたら白上応募しますけども！
What! If Washagana TV did something like that, I'd apply for it!
もちろんですよ！グッズの参考になると嬉しいです。
Of course! I'd be happy if this could be a reference for your merch.
ありがとうございました！告知も沢山いただきました。
Thank you very much! We got plenty of announcements too.
やっぱり力のあるところは出すもんが違いますね。
As expected, a big-shot's merch is on another level.
これとかさ、よく出来てんな。材質も良いし、
Like this one, it's really well-made. The material is good,
デザインも良く印刷されてる。
and the design is printed beautifully.
なんだ、何族だこれ？
Wait, what kind of tribe is this?
何族？
What tribe?
俺らの目の周りのアイマスク出しましょうよ。
Let's release eye masks based on our own eye areas.
実写のですか？
A live-action version?
俺がグラサンで、中村さんがドロンとした目の周りの感じ。
Me with sunglasses, and Nakamura-san's droopy eyes.
「ドロンとした」？
"Droopy"?
そこはぶくちゃんに描いて貰えば良い。
We can just have Buku-chan draw them.
いいですね、ぜひ出してください！
That sounds great, please do it!
たっぷりとおよそ50分近く収録して来ましたけど、
We've recorded for nearly 50 minutes,
大幅に切ります。20分くらいカットされますけど。
but we'll be cutting a lot. About 20 minutes will be cut.
もったいない！
What a waste!
さあ、どうだった？フブちゃん。
So, how was it, Fubu-chan?
楽しかったですね。時間もあっという間で、
It was fun. Time flew by,
もっとお話ししたかったんですけど、呼んで頂きましてありがとうございました！
and I wanted to talk more, but thank you so much for having me!
楽しかったんなら、うちの子になっちゃうかい？
If you had fun, why not become one of ours?
わあ！せつなクVTuberに。
Wow! As a Setsunaku VTuber.
取り分は均等に割るけどね。
We'll split the earnings equally, though.
大人の話は後でホロさんに。
We'll talk business with Holo-san later.
インターンっていう形とか、そういうのでご一緒できたらと！
Maybe as an intern or something, I'd love to work with you again!
あとで契約の面を、後ろでしっかりします。
We'll handle the contract details properly in the back later.
後ろで！
In the back!
やめてください、その愛情表現！キュンです。
Stop that expression of love! My heart is fluttering.
¥マネーにきゅんです。
Fluttering for the money.
最悪やもう。俺らの評価だけ下げてどうすんねん。
This is the worst. Why are you dragging down our reputation?
盛り上げてるだけですからね。エンタメです。
I'm just hyping it up. It's entertainment.
本当じゃないからね！フブちゃんとも仲良くやってますんで。
It's not real! We get along great with Fubu-chan.
本気にしないでくださいね、皆様。よろしくお願いします。
Please don't take it seriously, everyone. Thank you.
フブちゃん、ありがとうございました。いつもの締め、お願いします。
Fubu-chan, thank you very much. Please give us the usual closing.
はい！ご視聴ありがとうございました。
Okay! Thank you for watching.
白上フブキ、わしゃがなTVのチャンネル登録、
Please subscribe to Shirakami Fubuki and Washagana TV,
Twitterのフォローもよろしくお願いします！
and follow us on Twitter as well!
高評価、メンバーシップもよろしくね！
Please like the video and join the membership!
特報
Special News
わしゃがなTV 第4回 白上フブキゲスト出演決定！！
Washagana TV Vol. 4 - Shirakami Fubuki guest appearance confirmed!!
6/24(土) 21:00 ビジュアルアップデート お披露目決定
6/24 (Sat) 21:00 Visual Update reveal confirmed